[Music]
a new year is just around the corner and
my little part of the world world has
plunged into winter consequently I'm
visiting my family and their home for
some Festive Celebrations and could
think of no better way to start the day
than with
[Music]
pancakes last year I struggle to enjoy
winter to the fullest missing my long
hikes and afternoons sitting and reading
by the lake but this season is crucial
to the health of my Wilderness home for
the animals plants and humans alike so
this year I rededicated myself to a time
of wintering and there is nothing that
inspires me like the very first snow
where everything looks as if it's been
dusted with fine sugar and all is
glistening and perfect much like a
quaint little landscape painted on a
snowy
[Music]
afternoon though I was technically born
in the Autumn as a December baby I've
always sought to create a positive
relationship with the winter time as so
often on my birthday all that I can see
is blanketed and white and the
temperatures have plummeted one thing I
have been enjoying this month has been
going to cafes and holiday markets with
my family it's such a delightful
atmosphere to see the work of Artisans
and enjoy all the Cozy
[Music]
festivities
it's a good looking
[Music]
dog
all too aware of the impending New Year
I realize I rarely make a proper New
Year's resolution however I will share
something that has deeply helped me this
year overcome a lot of stress and worry
and it's that before I make any
lifestyle change I start with an inquiry
within so often I have friends tell me
they want to start spending more quality
time with their loved ones using their
phones less or exercising more often
this involves buying a lot of new gym
equipment or planning things out to an
amazing extent and all of these goals
are very well and good but in my
personal experience I've not been able
to apply true self-control without first
asking myself what is standing in the
way of making these changes what is it
within in my heart that is hindering my
journey towards who I want to be is it
pride or something harder to pinpoint
for me most of what was standing in my
own way of making permanent change was a
fear of some kind not always rational
but very
human examining that unur myself of
those suppressed emotions gave me more
energy and enthusiasm to make more
practical change I suppose nurturing my
soul first helped make my new lifestyle
of slowness and simplicity actually
happen it's not free of stressful
moments but it's far better than how I
lived
[Music]
before
perhaps when thinking of the new year
you don't know what you want to do with
your life where you want to go or what
direction you wish to take you may be at
a Crossroads or facing unknowns the one
thing that has guided me and is still
guiding me through enormous life change
is to be open to your inner world to
learn to question your fearful and
unhelpful thoughts and allow the waters
within to settle and clear to ever so
slowly reveal what it is you truly
desire to do with the time you have I'm
still figuring it out I have no idea how
my life will look like next year but I'm
excited to slowly find my
[Music]
way
for
[Music]
hi
that pretty
[Music]
keep
take
I have been working on these gingerbread
ornaments for a while now and I did
discover that I
absolutely uh got the wrong type of
icing the ingredients to make the icing
were so expensive at the grocery store
that I just couldn't rationalize buying
it for just a little ornament project
and I should have I should have because
this icing is not quite doing it for me
however I thought to make it more fun I
would just bring it over to a friend's
house or family and we could finish
decorating them together and not worry
too much about perfection which you know
why is it important honestly it's a
Christmas decoration so it's just about
having fun I think it's been a little
while since I've seen you thank you so
much for being here I am still adjusting
to a new pace of life with all these
huge changes I'm having doctor's
appointments fairly regularly about 2
hours away so sometimes it's a full day
trip sometimes two-day trip depending on
what needs to happen it is also holiday
season and for someone who works in
customer service there is a lot to be
said there too if you if you know you
know it can be chaotic to say the least
I'm doing my best to slow down and enjoy
this beautiful first snow we have it
just looks like one of those Thomas
cancade paintings where it's just
everything looks so cozy and so Laden
with this heavy blanket of snow
temperatures are going to warm up and
it's going to get really rainy soon so
I'm really enjoying the pristine beauty
while it lasts I'm wishing you the very
best for all the new things happening in
your life next year or whatever you're
looking forward to or if you were just
wanting to expand and grow it's been
very good for me as well to embrace a
season of acceptance of circumstances
and making changes that are also
realistic and practical and sustainable
for you something else has been that
I've had to enter this new era of huge
Acceptance in regards to work YouTube is
a place that I think very much rewards
creators when they upload often and
consistently and are very exciting and
currently I'm not really able to achieve
any of those things and I certainly knew
there would be consequences related to
that and I think it's been actually a
super positive thing for me to accept
that everything changes in time you
can't live expecting anything to stay
the same for too long you need to always
have your heart open to the positive
things that can come from change as well
as the challenges and that has been so
important for me lately I think I'm
going to take these gingerbread
ornaments to a friend's home and I will
hopefully be able to enjoy a little bit
more of the snow before the rain sets in
so I'm sending you all so much love
please leave your advice Below on how
you enjoy the winter season I know not
all of you are somewhere where you have
a winter season right now I'm just
sending you the best festive well wishes
for this upcoming New Year sending you
so so much love
goodbye